- [Instructor] So let's begin with the second part
of the solution to this challenge.
We're going to do lots of refactoring.
We're going to replace the React API with Zustand.
And first let's just make sure
that we add to the scope useStore like this.
And you see that we already have components,
multiple components that needs to be,
that needs to subscribe to the state changes
by calling this hook directly from the components.
So we have header, the header, the footer
and we can also create some other components like the form.
So I'm going to do that right away.
I'm going to put that in its own components.
I'm going to do that here.
So head to footers, so right below, actually, footer.
That's going to be function, it's going to be form.
And like this.
And we're going to do the same for the list right here.
So let's grab this unordered list
and put it in its own component.
So that's going to be function and then List, return.
And that's it.
So we just need to refer to this now
back in the main component.
So that's going to be first the form and the list.
So obviously we're not going to be doing any props drilling.
So here the goal is to keep the structure flat
and allow every components to subscribe
to the state changes independently.
So that's going to seem like a lot of refactoring.
You're going to see that we're going to be doing that step-by-step
but you'll see that the process is very simple.
First, let's start by moving anything related to the form
from the app to the form.
So I'm going to grab from line here to,
so we have submit, we have archive,
and I think that's it for now.
Let's go inside the form.
So I don't need this, actually, that's going to be here.
This one, I'm going to do that right away.
It's going to be inside the list.
Also for the form, we need to also have access to useRef.
So I'm going to add it here.
Actually, it's available here at the top.
I'm going to cut and add it to the form.
It's going to be handled directly from the form.
That's it.
And next I'm going to start removing.
So anything that we no longer need
on the app components, let's do that.
I'm going to remove that.
Same for check and archive here as well.
So we want to also to delete the props.
So it's already deleted, so that's great.
Okay, so let's move forward
and then start using the store data.
So we're going to call this from inside our component.
So that's going to be useStore.
And we want to access the functions like submit
and also archive.
So first we want to be able to update the state.
So read the state and update the state.
So let's do that now.
Here for submit, it's going to be submit.
We're going to pass the information of the new item.
And there is also this information right here
that we want to use as well, which is setInput.
We're going to be handling that.
So we're going to be using just very little the React API.
So when we know that this is just managed locally,
so I'm going to add this to my form components right below.
For archive I'm just going to change here the name
because you see that it conflicts.
So I'm going to say archiveAllitems.
So I'm going to change, and actually let's just remove
all of that because it's going to be handled, actually,
the logic is handled separately.
So let's just remove that.
I'm going to do onSubmit.
And for the archive, I believe that's,
I think I'm mistaking, okay, let's remove that.
It's actually handled from the footer.
So let's do that right away.
So I'm going to grab also the same hook and add in the footer
which is right at the top.
Right here.
So that's actually here that we're going to be handling
the archive function.
And same for filter but I think that for filter,
the name is different.
It's going to be setFilter, if I remember well.
Yeah, that is setFilter.
So let's just change that to setFilter like this.
And so we want to make sure that this is matching
what we want to do.
So here we have filters.
I'm going to change the name to setFilter like so.
And we have archive.
So I think that for the footer we are almost good to go.
Let's verify also for the header.
And for the header, we need to access
the information of the count.
And I think that for the count, actually, it's different.
It should be a useMemo.
So let's go back to the app component
where we have defined a computed here, a variable.
So with useMemo, so we're going to be using also useMemo
but this is handled, we know that we're using this
only locally, so let's go back to the header
and add this right here.
And that's the only thing that we need to use here.
So let's just all do that.
And actually no, I'm mistaking.
So we need to access all.
Let's go back, we need to access all.
Read the state and so we can from the existing state,
create derived data.
So this is what we're doing here.
And for the footer, we don't need submit.
And I'm going to remove also the props.
And you see that we also need here isVisible.
So let's grab also this from the app components.
I'm going to go grab this from the app component,
which is isVisible.
And add it...
It is inside the footer, should be here.
Because this button is going to be visible
only if items are crossed of the list.
And let's do the same for all items,
which is also available.
You see that we need this all items.
We need to grab this also from the app component.
So I'm going to cut this and add it to the list, this one.
And for this one, we also need to read the state
also by calling the hook.
So let's do that as well for the list.
And we need to access multiple information.
So for the check, actually let me also update that
because this is going to be handled actually
with the action which is defined in the store.
I don't need submit.
However, I'm going to need all.
I think it's good.
And now I'm just going to remove all of that
because no need to pass any states
or store data by using the props.
And let's remove that as well.
Okay, so if we try that.
So we're just going to make sure that this is up and running.
So let's try to run the app.
I'm going to make sure that I am in the right spot.
So that should be
the directory for the exercise demo
that corresponds to the video 06 of chapter five.
I'm going to go to the final one and then run npm start.
So here we're just missing one thing, which is filter.
So let's go check it out.
Filter should be, oh, here so we have
a better sense of what's missing.
So that's going to be inside the app.js line 44, line 45.
I'm going to check quickly.
This here, so we are missing,
so we don't read the state, which is all.
So let's update that as well.
Same for line 91, because that's a lot of refactoring.
We're going through lots of refactoring.
Archive, so I'm going to make sure that this is also,
I can access it from the store.
And then 135, which is lower.
Right here, so this is filter.
Or we're checking filter, so that should be yes.
We want to check which option it is so we know
which the status of the list either displaying
if it is active, completed or display all.
Finally in the store.
So I am missing something which is line 15 and 16.
And that's because we must remember
that we must actually read from first the store.
So I'm going to update that.
And same for all.
I'm going to update and we're going to be good to go.
I just need to remove one variable, which isn't used.
Let's go back to line 19.
And yeah, we don't need to use this one
because we access it from the store now.
So let's just run again for a final check.
And here we go.
So now we are ready to try our app again.
So this is up and running just nicely.
We can clear the items that are completed.
We can display just the active ones or the completed ones
or decide to display them all.
Excellent, so you see that with these examples
and this challenge that the setup with Zustand
is fast and easy with no fuss.
And also it is very familiar for any React developer.
So Zustand makes it very easy to manage
and access the state in your application
which makes it a very friendly alternative
to all the state management solutions.